Guide to the Philip G. Zimbardo Papers
Stanford University Libraries
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Philip G. Zimbardo papers
1953-2004
SC0750
Zimbardo, Philip G.
1.5 Linear feet
These papers contain typescript papers and articles, 1966-2003; miscellaneous departmental and other files, 1969-2004; and his articles, reviews, and other publications, 1953-2003.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Stanford University Libraries 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://www-sul.stanford.edu/depts/spc/spc.html
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Philip G. Zimbardo, nationally known for his research on shyness, prisons, and violence, joined the Stanford faculty in the Dept. of Psychology in 1968. He earned his Ph.D. at Yale University in 1959 and taught at New York University and Columbia before coming to Stanford. He has received numerous awards for his teaching and research and served as president of the American Psychological Association in 2002.
Description of the Collection
These papers contain typescript papers and articles, 1966-2003; miscellaneous departmental and other files, 1969-2004; and his articles, reviews, and other publications, 1953-2003.
Access Terms
Stanford University--Faculty.; Stanford University. Dept. of Psychology; Zimbardo, Philip G.; Psychology--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Original Accession, Accession ARCH-2005-031
  - Typescript Papers, Chapters, and Reports
    - "The Chilling Effect of Surveillance: Deindividuation and Reactance," ONR Technical Report Z-15, May 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Constructing Time After Death: The Transcendental-Future Time Perspective," ca. 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Corrections: Perspectives on Research, Policy and Impact," ONR Technical Report Z-13, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Effects of system and social variables on gender differences in communication and team decision making," ONR Technical Report Z-82-02, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "The Modification of Selective Recall of Central and Incidental Task Features by Emotional Arousal," ONR Technical Report Z-02, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "A Passion for Psychology: Teaching it Charismatically, Writing about it Engagingly, and Integrating Teaching and Research Synergistically," ca. 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "The personal and cultural dynamics of shyness: a comparison between Israelis, American Jews and Americans," ca. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Physical Integration and Social Segregation of Northern Negro College Students (1953, 1963 and 1965)," 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "The Political Psychology of Terrorist Alarms," 2003 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "The Politics of Persuasion," ONR Technical Report Z-06, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "Present Time Perspective as a Predictor of Risky Driving" (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "Psychological and system variables in team problem solving: Experimental studies of computer-mediated participation," ONR Technical Report Z-82-01, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "The Psychology of Evil: A Situationist Perspective on Recruiting Good People to Engage in Anti-Social Acts," ca. 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Sexism Springs Eternalin The Reader's Digest," April 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "Shame and Anger in Chronic Shyness," 1998 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - "The Silent Prison of Shyness," November 1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "Social Determinants of Group Loyalty, Innovation, and Activism," ONR Technical Report Z-11 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "A Social-Psychological Analysis of Vandalism: Making Sense of Senseless Violence," ONR Technical Report Z-05, Dec. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Stanford Time Perspective Inventory (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "Whose Time It Is I Think I Know: Research on Time Perspectives," 1994 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Assorted writings (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Departmental and other papers
    - Miscellaneous materials, 2003-04 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Psychology 1 syllabus, Winter 1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Psychology Trading Cards - Zimbardo (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Retirement party, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Stanford University psychology Ph.D.'s 1912-1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Stanford University psychology students 1968-93 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Publications
    - Bibliography (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1950s (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1960-61 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1964-65 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1967-68 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1970: Canvassing for Peace (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1974-75 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 1978-79 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 1980-84 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 1985-89 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 1991-95 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 1996-99 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 2000-2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)